http://www.caslab.com/en/privacy-statement

Privacy Statement
Home
ALS Limited and its related entities (“the ALS Group”, “we or “us”) are committed to protecting privacy, and the fair, lawful and transparent collection and processing of the Personal Data it receives. This Policy details how the ALS Group collects, processes and manages Personal Data.
For the purposes of this Policy, “Personal Data” means information that, separately or collectively, enables a person to be identified, directly or indirectly, as an individual.
The types of Personal Data collected and how it is collected
The ALS Group collects Personal Data in a transparent manner from a range of individuals in a variety of ways for its business purposes. Personal Data collected may include a person’s name, gender, home or postal address, job title, date of birth, photographic image, email address, telephone number, mobile phone number, business interests, academic qualifications and experience, professional associations and memberships, bank account details and service preferences.
Personal Data is collected when an individual calls or writes to us; visits one of our sites or offices; enquires about our services or we provide services to them; offers to, or provides, services to us; interacts with our websites; enquires as to, or applies, for a job with us; and works for us, with us, or on our behalf. Personal Data may also be collected from third-party sources, such as government bodies, credit agencies, or from publicly available records or sources of information.
Sometimes sensitive Personal Data revealing racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, trade union membership, health or medical conditions, genetic or biometric information, sexual orientation, or criminal convictions and offences is collected where an individual has provided this information to us or has otherwise consented to its collection, or for us to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
The basis for processing your Personal Data
Personal Data is only processed where we have a lawful reason to do so, including:
where you have provided your consent;
to perform a contract that we have in place with you;
our other legitimate business interests, including undertaking due diligence; to monitor compliance with our policies and standards; and to protect and secure our premises and systems; and
to comply with our legal and regulatory obligations.
Personal Data may also be processed for related or ancillary purposes to the above where it could reasonably be expected that such processing would occur.
Marketing
Personal Data is not used for marketing purposes in countries where consent is required for this purpose, unless that consent has been provided. You can choose not to receive marketing communications from us at any time.
Sharing of Personal Data
Personal Data may be shared within the ALS Group to provide you with the services you have requested or for us to administer our relationship with you. Employees within the ALS Group are required to maintain the confidentiality and security of Personal Data and to only process Personal Data in accordance with this Policy.
Personal Data may be shared with third parties, such as our suppliers and service providers, where we have engaged them to perform services on our behalf; or where we have a lawful reason or legal obligation to do so e.g. to comply with a court order or a request from one of our regulators.
Where Personal Data is disclosed to third parties who perform services for us, we require the third party to treat the Personal Data in accordance with this Policy and as required by applicable data protection and privacy laws.
Personal Data of others provided to us
If you provide Personal Data about another person (e.g. one of your employees, someone you do business with, or a family member) to us, you must ensure that you are authorised to provide that information to us, and that we may collect, process and manage that Personal Data as set out in this Policy.
Securing Personal Data
The ALS Group implements appropriate industry-standard administrative, technical, organisational and physical safeguards that are intended to protect Personal Data against unauthorised or unlawful processing; and against accidental loss, misuse, unlawful destruction or deletion, or unauthorised alteration or disclosure.
Transferring Personal Data
As a global organisation, Personal Data may be transferred abroad if required for the purpose for which it was provided to us and in accordance with this Policy.
In providing Personal Data, you agree and consent to the transfer of your Personal Data to another country. When transferring Personal Data abroad, adequate safeguards to protect Personal Data are put in place.
Retention of Personal Data
Personal Data is deleted or destroyed when it is no longer required, or where deletion of it has been requested and we are not legally required to retain it.
Respecting rights
The ALS Group recognises rights in relation to Personal Data, including an individual’s right to:
request the Personal Data held about them;
obtain a copy of their Personal Data;
update or correct their Personal Data;
request deletion of their Personal Data;
withdraw their consent to the processing of their Personal Data;
object to the processing of their Personal Data; and
have their Personal Data transferred to another data controller.
The ALS Group also recognises the right of an individual to make a complaint if they have a concern about our handling of their Personal Data.
If you wish to do any of the above, please refer to the Contact Us section of this Policy. Requests will be responded to within the timeframe required by the applicable data protection and privacy laws, or otherwise, within a reasonable period of time.
Should you not be satisfied with our handling of your request or our handing of your Personal Data, you can contact the relevant privacy regulator or supervisory authority to make a compliant.
Cookies
ALS Group websites use cookies to help provide the best experience when interacting with these websites. Cookies are small text files that are stored on a device when a person visits a website. A web browser can be configured to reject or delete cookies however this may cause websites to have limited functionality.
Cookies are used to make our websites work as expected; to save having to login every time to a certain section of a website visited; to remember individual settings during and between website visits; and to improve the speed and security of our websites.
The ALS Group does not use cookies to personally identify an individual who visits its websites.
Accessing other websites via hyperlink
ALS Group websites provide access to other websites via hyperlinks that are owned and operated by third parties which are not subject to this Policy. As we do not have any control over these websites, you should review the privacy policy of each of the websites before you access them to decide whether that website’s privacy policy is acceptable to you.
Updates to this Privacy Policy
Updates to this Policy may be made from time to time to reflect any changes to the way we collect, process and manage Personal Data. Updates will be posted to www.alsglobal.com and on the ALS Group’s intranet, with updates taking effect from the time of posting.
Contact us
If you have questions or concerns about the way we collect, use or manage Personal Data, please contact us via the contact us link on www.alsglobal.com or write to:
The Privacy Officer
ALS Limited
PO Box 66
Everton Park QLD 4053
Australia
Effective: 12 March 2014
Last updated:  12 October 2020
Have a question?
Need a quote?
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Transportable Moisture Limit (TML) & Flow Moisture Point (FMP)
Transportable Moisture Limit (TML) & Flow Moisture Point (FMP)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Transportable Moisture Limit (TML) & Flow Moisture Point (FMP)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Electro-Magnetic Acoustic Transducer (EMAT)
Long Range Ultrasonic Testing (LRUT)
Phased Array Ultrasonic Testing (PAUT)
Photogrammetry
Pulsed Eddy Current Testing (PECT)
Saturated Low Frequency Eddy Current (SLOFEC)
Short Range Guided Wave (SRGW)
Time of Flight Diffraction (TOFD)
Transportable Moisture Limit (TML) & Flow Moisture Point (FMP)
Legionella testing for hospitals health and aged care facilities
Environmental Monitoring Program (EMP)
Mine site laboratories (operate)
Salt Lake City - Industrial Hygiene, Dietary Supplements, Mycology
Vancouver - Geochemistry (Lab)
Vancouver - Geochemistry (Sample Prep)
Bangkok - Environmental, Food, Pharmaceutical, Consumer Products
Brisbane - Geochemistry (Sample Preparation)
Perth - Geochemistry (Analytical)
Perth - Oil, fuel & coolant analysis
Perth - Laboratory design and build
Perth - Geochemistry (Sample Preparation)
Jeddah - Environmental,
